# **BHANU CHANDRA K**

### **Technical Architect**

+(91) 9535226978 ur.bhanu@gmail.com

Result oriented professional with over **19** years of experience. Rich product development experience in cloud platform, networking and Al/ML. Ability to lead a team and can work as an individual. Astute planner/leader with exemplary communication, relationship management, Strong analytical, organizational, leadership and problem-solving skills.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Technical Architect - Aarna Networks (2020 - Present)

- Led product development initiatives with end-to-end responsibility for system architecture and design decisions for cloud-native platforms supporting AI infrastructure workloads.
- Provided technical leadership and governance, mentoring team members and enforcing design/code best practices. Led technical evaluations and proof-of-concepts (PoCs) to assess new technologies for integration into product roadmap to drive innovation in AI/ML workload management.
- Participated in customer demos and supported solution engineering efforts during client interactions.
  Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure alignment with business and technical goals.
- Contributed to open-source projects such as ORAN-SC, Nephio, and ONAP, enhancing community-driven telecom and cloud-native solutions. Designed and developed an end-to-end Service Management and Orchestration platform compliant with O-RAN specifications, integrating with multiple RAN vendors. Possess deep domain expertise in RAN systems and Al-driven RAN (Al-RAN) technologies.

## Principal Engineer - Western Digital (2015 - 2020)

- Designed and developed the ActiveScale Cloud Management and Data Analytics Platform, enabling large-scale data storage and insights.
- Built and maintained RESTful APIs to support analytics workflows and cloud service integration. Performed data analysis and processing on the Hadoop ecosystem, including development of MapReduce jobs and management of HDFS clusters for both production and development environments on AWS.
- Led a team in building critical features for DAO (Data Analytics Orchestrator), enabling deployment of AI/ML models at distributed factory locations for real-time decision making.

## Member Technical Staff - Aruba networks (2013 - 2015)

- Contributed to the design and development of Aruba Central, a cloud-based Wi-Fi management solution for Instant WLANs using self-organizing access points.
- Added switch support and enhanced multiple modules, focusing on scalability, performance, and seamless cloud integration. Collaborated on product design and implementation of core features, ensuring alignment with overall system architecture and functional requirements.

# Lead Engineer - Netscout Systems (2009 - 2013)

• Part of the core development team and developed a product from scratch which monitors enterprise networks.

Programmer Analyst - Cognizant (2006 - 2009)

### **EDUCATION**

- **B.Tech**, JNTU Hyderabad
- M.Tech, JNTU Kakinada

#### **SKILLS**

- Java, Go, Python
- Gogin, Flask, spring, hibernate
- postgres, Mysql, cassandra, redis
- kafka, rabbitmq
- Ray, kuberay, vllm, HF train
- kubernetes, openshift, docker
- ELK, prometheus, grafana, cortex
- AWS, GCP
- Ansible, Terraform, pulumi